<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</title>
    <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 19:16:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jackies Cheese Cake</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-11-29-jackies-cheese-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 19:16:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-11-29-jackies-cheese-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients&amp;hellip;
 250g digestive biscuits 120g melted butter 400g plain cream cheese 50g icing sugar 450g single (33%) cream 300g white chocolate  Method
Blitz biscuits Add the melted butter Mix well &amp;amp; Refrigerate for 30 minutes
Whip up the cream cheese &amp;amp; Add icing sugar
Whip 300g of single cream
Add whipped single cream to the cream cheese &amp;amp; icing sugar mixture and fold together
Place the wet mixture on the cooled biscuit base</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand Biscuits</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-04-21-new-zealand-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-04-21-new-zealand-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 4 ozs sugar 4 ozs butter 1 heaped tablespoon of Golden Syrup 2 ozs dessicated coconut 3 ozs rolled oats 4 ozs plain flour 2 level teaspoons bicarbonate of soda  Method
Melt the butter with the sugar &amp;amp; golden syrup then let it bubble for approx. 2 minutes
Add the dry ingredients &amp;amp; mix well
Place walnut sized portions (well spaced) on to a well greased baking sheet, approx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancakes</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-16-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-16-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 100g plain flour 2 eggs Pinch of salt 300ml milk 1 tsp of sunflower oil  Method
Whisk together until it is a batter Leave for, at least, 30 minutes to rest Then fry - butter pan&amp;hellip;
BBC Good Food (&amp;ldquo;Easy Pancakes&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-14-french-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-14-french-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS
 3 pounds sweet onions, thinly sliced 4 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted 2 teaspoons brown sugar 2 teaspoons sherry vinegar 1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce 5 fresh thyme sprigs 3 bay leaves 6 cups beef stock Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 (12-ounce) French baguette, sliced 2 cups Gruyère cheese, shredded  Method
Add the thinly sliced onions to a 6-qt slow cooker. Stir in butter, brown sugar, 1 teaspoon salt, sherry vinegar and Worcestershire sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbread Loaf</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-01-27-gingerbread-loaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-01-27-gingerbread-loaf/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients&amp;hellip;
 175g unsalted butter, diced, plus extra for greasing 175g light muscovado sugar 175g black treacle 200ml whole milk 2 large free-range eggs, beaten 250g plain flour 1½ tsp bicarbonate of soda ½ tsp mixed spice 2 tsp ground ginger  Method
Preheat the oven to 180°C/fan160°C/gas 4. Grease and line a 1.5kg loaf tin.
Melt together the butter, sugar and treacle, stirring until the sugar has dissolved. Remove from the heat and stir in the milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Brownies</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-01-04-christmas-brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-01-04-christmas-brownies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 30ml/1fl oz brandy 100g/3½oz dried cranberries 300g/10½oz dark chocolate, broken into chunks 200g/7oz butter 4 free-range eggs 300g/10½oz light muscovado sugar 200g/7oz plain flour 1 tsp mixed spice 100g/3½oz pecans, roughly chopped icing sugar, to serve  Method
Preheat the oven to 180C/350F/Gas 4 and line a 30x20cm/12x8in tin with baking parchment.
Gently heat the brandy then add the cranberries and leave to soak while you prepare the brownie mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-12-04-baked-rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-12-04-baked-rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:
 250g pudding (short grain) rice 1200ml milk 70g caster sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla extract Pinch of Cinammon 4 tablespoons brown sugar Whipped cream to serve  Method:
Preheat oven to 150 degrees C Place the pudding rice in a ceramic dish In a saucepan, place the milk, caster sugar and vanilla extract. Bring to the boil. Pour the boiling liquid over the rice and cover the ceramic dish with tin foil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NI Vegetable Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-ni-vegetable-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-ni-vegetable-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 500g soup vegetables (2 carrots, 5 sticks of celery - including the leaves, 2-3 leeks &amp;amp; flat leaf parsley) 100 - 200g marrowfat peas (soaked overnight), lentils, barley 2 / 2.5 litres of stock - vegetable &amp;amp; chicken Salt &amp;amp; Pepper  Method
Make stock, add peas (lentils/barley) bring to the boil &amp;amp; simmer gently for at least 20 minutes (until peas tender ish)
Add chopped vegetables &amp;amp; bring back to the boil and simmer for at least 25 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parkin Ginger Cake</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-parkin-ginger-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-parkin-ginger-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 12oz golden syrup 6oz butter or baking margarine 8oz black treacle 13oz oats 3 eggs 7oz self-raising flour 9oz dark brown sugar 3 tsp milk 3 tsp ginger powder  Method
Mix together the golden syrup, butter and black treacle.
Pop them in the microwave for two minutes to loosen up.
Pour the mixture into a large bowl of oats, and stir.
Add the remaining ingredients (eggs, flour, sugar, milk and ginger powder) and mix well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Pudding</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-sticky-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-sticky-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
For the pudding:  125g butter 1 tbsp golden syrup 1 tbsp black treacle 2 large free range eggs 1 tsp vanilla extract 150g self-raising flour 150g light muscovado sugar 150g medjool dates, chopped 2 tsp bicarbonate soda Tub of vanilla ice cream, to serve  **For the sauce: **
 100g unsalted butter 150g dark muscovado sugar 3 tbsp golden syrup 150ml double cream 1 tsp vanilla extract Generous pinch sea salt  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cath&#39;s Carrot Cake &amp; Frosting</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-05-11-caths-carrot-cake-frosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-05-11-caths-carrot-cake-frosting/</guid>
      <description>Carrot cake ingredients
 2 cups of sugar 1 ½ cups of vegetable oil (NOT olive oil!) 3 eggs 2 teaspoons of Vanilla Essence 2 ¼ cups of Self-raising flour 2 teaspoons of Ground Cinnamon 2 teaspoons of Baking Soda 1 teaspoon of Salt 2 cups of shredded Carrot 2 cups of flaked Coconut 18 oz can of crushed Pineapple (drained) 1 cup of chopped Walnuts (try some Sultanas)  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rick Stein Tarte flambee</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-17-rick-stein-tarte-flambee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-17-rick-stein-tarte-flambee/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time
less than 30 mins
Cooking time
10 to 30 mins
Serves
Serves 4 as a main or 12 as a snack
Ingredients
For the dough
 250g/9oz plain flour, sifted, plus extra for dusting 1/2 tsp salt 150ml/5fl oz tepid water 2 tbsp sunflower oil  For the topping
 160g/51/2oz smoked bacon lardons 250g/9oz full-fat creme fraiche 1 large onion, thinly sliced 250g/9oz Emmental or Gruyere, or a mixture, grated whole nutmeg, for grating salt and freshly ground black pepper  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rick Stein&#39;s Seafood Gratin</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-rick-steins-seafood-gratin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-rick-steins-seafood-gratin/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time less than 30 mins
Cooking time 30 mins to 1 hour
Serves Serves 6
Ingredients
 450ml/16fl oz fish stock (see tip) 400g/14oz white fish fillets (such as cod), skinned and cut into 2cm/¾in pieces 200g/7oz scallops, removed from the shell and cleaned 400g/14oz raw prawns, peeled and deveined 50ml/2fl oz white wine 150ml/5fl oz full-fat milk 100ml/3½fl oz double cream 50g/1¾oz butter, plus extra for greasing 2 leeks, trimmed, halved lengthways and sliced 50g/1¾oz plain flour small handful fresh flatleaf parsley, roughly chopped 80g/2¾oz emmental cheese, grated 50g/1¾oz panko breadcrumbs salt and freshly ground black pepper crusty bread, cut into chunks, to serve  For the caramelised apples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salted Caramel Sauce</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-salted-caramel-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-salted-caramel-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 2 tbsps caster sugar 3 tbsps double cream 1 tbsp butter Pinch of sea salt flakes  Method
Put the sugar and 2 tbsps water in a small heavy bottomed saucepan. Place on a low heat and swirl gently until the sugar has melted. Turn up the heat and let the sugar bubble and caramelise to a nutty brown. Take off the heat and pour in the cream, butter and salt flakes - do this carefully, as it may split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Jammie Biscuits</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-simple-jammie-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-04-14-simple-jammie-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Makes 12
 200g self-raising flour 100g caster sugar 100g butter 1 egg, lightly beaten 4 tbsp strawberry jam  Heat oven to 190°c/170°c Fan/gas 5
Method
Rub the flour, sugar and butter together with your fingertips until the mixture resembles breadcrumbs.
Add enough egg to bring the mixture together to form a stiff dough.
Flour your hands and shape the dough into a sausage, about 5cm in diameter. Cut into 2cm slices and place on a large baking sheet, well spaced, as they will spread when baking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persimmon Cookies</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-10-28-persimmon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-10-28-persimmon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 150g Hachiya persimmon pulp (about 2 to 3 persimmons, skins removed) 1 teaspoon baking soda 150g cup sugar 75g butter, at room temperature 1 egg, beaten 300g flour 1 teaspoon cinnamon ½ teaspoon nutmeg ½ teaspoon salt 150g chopped walnuts 150g raisins  Method
  Preheat the oven to 375°F. In a large mixing bowl, beat the persimmon pulp, soda, sugar, and butter until creamy. Beat the egg separately, then fold it into the persimmon mixture, along with the flour, cloves, cinnamon, nutmeg, salt, walnuts, and raisins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butternut and Red Pepper Quiche</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-butternut-and-red-pepper-quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-butternut-and-red-pepper-quiche/</guid>
      <description>Prep Time 45 mins - Cook Time 35 mins - Total Time 1 hr 20 mins
Servings: 4
Ingredients
FOR THE BASE:
 3 med potatoes Olive oil Salt &amp;amp; Pepper  FOR THE QUICHE:
 1 large red pepper 3 tbsp apple cider vinegar 1 tbsp white vinegar 1 cup water 1 large butternut squash 1 onion 3 cloves garlic 1 tsp Mixed herbs Salt &amp;amp; Pepper 40 g Feta cheese chopped up small you can add more cheese if you like 5 eggs lightly beaten  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Cheese Crust Tomato Quiche</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-easy-cheese-crust-tomato-quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-easy-cheese-crust-tomato-quiche/</guid>
      <description>Prep Time 20 mins - Cook Time 35 mins - Total Time 55 mins
Ingredients
FOR THE CRUST:
 2 1/8 cups wholewheat flour 1/4 cup olive oil 2 egg yolks keep the egg whites aside for later 3/4 cup milk 1 cup cheddar cheese grated 1 tsp dried mixed herbs  FOR THE QUICHE:
 8 eggs whisked + the 2 egg whites set aside earlier 1 tsp mixed dried herbs 1 cup cheddar cheese grated 1/2 tsp salt 1 tsp black pepper 4 large tomatoes sliced into thin rounds  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skillet Potatoes with Chorizo and Fried Eggs</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-skillet-potatoes-with-chorizo-and-fried-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-skillet-potatoes-with-chorizo-and-fried-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 750g baby potatoes, cut into quarters 1 tbsp rapeseed oil 1 large onion, thinly sliced 2 garlic cloves, finely sliced 125g chorizo ring, sliced thickly 1 tbsp fresh rosemary, finely chopped 270g Vittoria tomatoes, halved 4 eggs ½ tsp chipotle chilli flakes  Method
  Preheat the oven to 200°C/gas mark 6. Boil the potatoes for 10 minutes until tender. Drain and leave to cool.   Meanwhile, heat the oil in a large skillet or shallow casserole dish and add the onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Vegetable Curry</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-vegan-vegetable-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-vegan-vegetable-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 1 tbsp vegetable oil 1 large onion, finely chopped 5cm piece ginger, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 red chilli, finely chopped 1 heaped tsp ground cumin 1 heaped tsp ground coriander 1 heaped tsp ground turmeric 1 aubergine, chopped into 1cm pieces 400g tin chopped tomatoes 200ml vegan-friendly hot vegetable stock 1 courgette, chopped into 1 cm pieces 300g basmati rice 100g spinach 150g peas (fresh or defrosted if frozen) chopped fresh coriander, to serve  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mieke&#39;s New Zealand Biscuits</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-08-22-miekes-new-zealand-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-08-22-miekes-new-zealand-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 4ozs sugar 4ozs butter 1 heaped tablespoon Golden Syrup 2 ozs desiccated coconut 3 ozs rolled oats 4ozs plain flour 2 level teaspoons bicarbonate of soda  Method
 Melt the butter with the sugar and golden syrup then let it bubble for approx 2 minutes. Add the dry ingredients and mix well. Place walnut sized portions (well spaced) on to a well-greased baking sheet, approx 12 to a sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Pot Chicken Chow Mein</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-08-17-one-pot-chicken-chow-mein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-08-17-one-pot-chicken-chow-mein/</guid>
      <description>An easy, one pot Chicken Chow Mein loaded with vegetables and ready in 30 minutes!
Servings 6 Calories 392kcal
Ingredients
 1 tablespoon canola oil 3 boneless skinless chicken breasts, cubed 1 red pepper diced 1 cup stringless snap peas 3 cups shredded cabbage or coleslaw mix 2 large carrot peeled and shredded 1 teaspoon minced garlic 1/2 teaspoon minced ginger 1-2 pinches red pepper flakes 4 cups chicken broth 1/2 cup soy sauce 1/4 cup hoisin sauce 375 g box whole grain spaghettini pasta 2 tablespoons water 1 tablespoon cornflour  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese and Tomato Quiche</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-06-24-cheese-and-tomato-quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-06-24-cheese-and-tomato-quiche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
FOR THE CRUST:
 2 1/8 cups wholewheat flour 1/4 cup olive oil 2 egg yolks keep the egg whites aside for later 3/4 cup milk 1 cup cheddar cheese grated 1 tsp dried mixed herbs  FOR THE QUICHE:
 8 eggs whisked + the 2 egg whites set aside earlier 1 tsp mixed dried herbs 1 cup cheddar cheese grated 1/2 tsp salt 1 tsp black pepper 4 large tomatoes sliced into thin rounds  Instructions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacio e pepe</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-09-cacio-e-pepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-09-cacio-e-pepe/</guid>
      <description>Made with only four ingredients, and ready in just 20 minutes, this cacio e pepe (which literally translates as cheese and pepper), is a brilliant Italian supper that&amp;rsquo;s super simple to make and tastes absolutely divine. See method
Serves 4
 5 mins to prepare and 15 mins to cook 546 calories / serving  Ingredients
 400g bucatini or spaghetti 60g butter 60g butter 1 tbsp freshly ground black pepper 100g Parmesan, grated  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Cordial</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-07-lemon-cordial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-07-lemon-cordial/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 7-10 unwaxed lemons 650g granulated sugar  Method
Scrub lemons and zest four of them. Bring a saucepan of water to the boil, add lemons and leave for 1 minute. Lemons are often quite hard and unyielding - this softens them so they give more juice when squeezed.
Remove lemons and reserve lemon-infused water. Juice lemons. Put sugar, lemon zest and 500 millilitres lemon-infused water into a saucepan. Heat gently to dissolve sugar, then bring to the boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Curd</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-07-lemon-curd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-05-07-lemon-curd/</guid>
      <description>Makes 1 x 200g Jar
Ingredients
 2 lemons, zest and juice 100g caster sugar 50g butter 2 eggs, beaten  Method
Put the lemon zest, juice, sugar and butter in a heatproof bowl over a pan of simmering water. Stir occasionally until the butter has melted. Then, using a small whisk or fork, stir in the beaten egg. Keep gently whisking the mixture over the heat for around 10 mins until thickened like custard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caramelise Onions</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-04-24-caramelise-onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-04-24-caramelise-onions/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 25-30g butter 2 - 3 large onions (red or white), thinly sliced pinch of salt  Tasty additions
 2 tbsp soft brown sugar 1-2 tbsp balsamic vinegar  How to caramelise onions
  Heat the oil in a large deep frying pan over a low heat.
  Add the onions with a generous pinch of salt and cook slowly for around 15-20 mins. Stir occasionally to prevent them from sticking or burning until they become soft and a golden caramel colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Cheese Sauce</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-04-15-white-cheese-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-04-15-white-cheese-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
250ml milk
25 grams butter
2 tablespoons flour
(50g cheese)
Method
Whisk fast as the butter melts and the mixture comes to the boil - the flour will disappear and the sauce will begin to thicken. Whisk for 2 minutes while the sauce bubbles and becomes nice &amp;amp; thick.
(Add cheese to make it cheese sauce)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Really Sticky Ribs</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-02-11-really-skicky-ribs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-02-11-really-skicky-ribs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 400ml / 14 fl.oz Tomato Passata 2 garlic cloves, crushed 2 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp clear honey 1 tbsp worcestershire sauce 1kg / 2lb 4oz pork ribs  Method
In a large bowl, mix together the passata, garlic, soy sauce, honey &amp;amp; worcestershire sauce. Add the pork ribs to the bowl &amp;amp; mix well to coat evenly. Tip the ribs and all the sauce into the pressure cooker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-12-11-recipe-for-french-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-12-11-recipe-for-french-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>WHOLE CHICKEN STOCK
 1 whole chicken (about 4 to 5 pounds), remove any paper or big fat globs inside the bird 1 yellow onion, quartered 2 carrots, scrubbed and cut in half 2 celery stalks (with leaves if possible), cut in half 5 garlic cloves, smashed open, skin removed 2 large bay leaves 5 sprigs fresh thyme 5 stems fresh parsley 1 tablespoon sea salt 1/2 teaspoon whole black peppercorns water to cover chicken – at least 4 quarts  METHOD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bow Bell Fat Free Tea Loaf</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-20-bow-bell-fat-free-tea-loaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-20-bow-bell-fat-free-tea-loaf/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 500ml of brewed tea I lb (454g) brown sugar 2 eggs 1.5 lb (680g) sultanas 1.25 lb (567g) self raising flour 1 tsp baking powder 1 tsp bicarbonate of soda 1 tsp mixed spice (optional)  Method
Steep the fruit, sugar and tea overnight in a bowl
Heat oven to 160 °C or 320°F or Gas Mark 3
Mix all ingredients together adding a little mixed spice if you&amp;rsquo;d like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean Enchiladas</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-16-bean-enchiladas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-16-bean-enchiladas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 2tbsp olive oil 2 red onions, finely diced 6 mixed peppers, seeded &amp;amp; diced 6 garlic cloves, finely grated 2 chillies, seeded &amp;amp; finely chopped 1 litre tomato passata 1 tbsp caster sugar 1 tsp ground coriander 2 tsp ground ginger??? Lime juice Coriander Black beans/kidney beans Spinach - frozen Wraps  Method
Passata below &amp;amp; above once wrapped &amp;amp; grated cheese (or substitute on top) and into oven 200°c/180°c fan/gas 6 20 minutes)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granola Bars</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-10-granola-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-11-10-granola-bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 170g Soft light brown sugar 75g Golden syrup 75ml Apple juice 200g Sugar free muesli 200g Granola 200g Any combination of dried fruit/nuts/seeds  Method
Heat oven to 180°C or 350°F or Gas mark 4. Line a baking tray 30 x 20 cm with baking parchment. Put sugar, syrup, butter, apple juice in pan and gently bring to boil. Remove from heat and stir in all other ingredients, mix well and transfer to prepared tin, press mixture with a fork until well packed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronation Chicken</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-07-16-coronation-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-07-16-coronation-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 3 tablespoons Mayonnaise 1 tablespoon Mango Chutney 1 teaspoon Sharwoods Medium Curry Powder Sultanas - optional  Method
Add cooked chicken, shredded if possible</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Soda Bread</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-07-16-vegan-soda-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-07-16-vegan-soda-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingreidents
 200g plain flour 150g wholemeal flour 50g oats (I use 20g oats + 30g of seed mix) &amp;amp; extra to sprinkle on top 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon baking soda 300ml neutral tasting dairy free milk 1 tablespoon white wine vinegar or lemon juice  Method
Mix all dry ingredients together, then add milk (which has been curdled by previously adding white wine vinegar/lemon juice)
1lb loaf tin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date and Coconut Balls</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-03-01-date-and-coconut-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-03-01-date-and-coconut-balls/</guid>
      <description>One of my go-to recipes that I can make up in bulk and grab before I head out the door is this one for date and coconut balls. You can freeze them as well which is a bonus, but they will keep for a couple of weeks in an airtight container in the fridge. Depends how delicious you find them – ahem&amp;hellip;!!
 Ingredients:
 120g dates 80g jumbo mixed raisins 20g desiccated coconut, plus 2tbsps to coat 20g porridge oats A tablespoon of coconut oil   Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Pot Chicken Chow Mein</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-28-one-pot-chicken-chow-mein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-28-one-pot-chicken-chow-mein/</guid>
      <description>Prep Time 10 mins
Cook Time 20 mins
An easy, one pot Chicken Chow Mein loaded with vegetables and ready in 30 minutes!
Ingredients
 1 tablespoon canola oil 2 boneless skinless chicken breasts, cubed 1 red pepper diced 1 cup stringless snap peas 1 1/2 cups shredded cabbage or coleslaw mix 1 large carrot peeled and shredded 1 teaspoon minced garlic 1/2 teaspoon minced ginger 1-2 pinches red pepper flakes 4 cups chicken broth 1/2 cup soy sauce 1/4 cup hoisin sauce 1 375 g box whole grain spaghettini pasta  Instructions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediterranean Vegetable Tart</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-14-mediterranean-vegetable-tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-14-mediterranean-vegetable-tart/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time: 1 - 2 hours
Cooking time: 1 - 2 hours
Serves 4
Dietary: Vegetarian
You can vary the vegetables and herbs in this puff pastry tart according to what you have. Leave yourself an extra hour preparation so that the pastry has time to rest.
Each serving provides 400 kcals, 13g protein, 43g carbohydrates (of which 8.5g sugars) 18.5g fat (of which 10g saturates), 6g fibre and 0.7g salt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBQ Sauce Patricks Recipe Flix</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-13-bbq-sauce-patricks-recipe-flix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-13-bbq-sauce-patricks-recipe-flix/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 Ketchup Honey / Brown Sugar - 15ml Dark Soy Sauce - 15ml Ground Ginger - 5ml Ground Black Pepper Finely chopped fat Garlic Clove L&amp;amp;P Worcestershire Sauce Lemon Juice - 5ml  Method
 make less &amp;amp; add items to taste such as Chilli Powder / Fresh Chilli  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-13-frenc-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-02-13-frenc-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>Makes: Enough for 4
Takes: 3 hours
Bakes: No time at all
Ingredients
 1 kg brown onions (unpeeled weight) 40g butter 1 tablespoon olive oil 2 tablespoons plain flour 100ml Sherry 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar 800ml beef stock 4-8 slices of French stick 150g gruyere   Peel, top and tail the onions and cut into slivers. Melt the butter with the oil in a large heavy-bottomed pan. Put the onions in the pan, and stir so that everything gets a good coating of the butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighter Southern-style Chicken with Potato Salad</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-01-04-lighter-southern-style-chicken-with-potato-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-01-04-lighter-southern-style-chicken-with-potato-salad/</guid>
      <description>Preparation time overnight
Cooking time 30 mins to 1 hour
Serves 4
Enjoy a lighter version of Southern-style chicken.
Its mouth-watering secret is a low-fat buttermilk marinade and a crispy crumb packed with flavour.
Each serving provides:
509 kcal 63g protein
42g carbohydrates (of which 6g sugars)
7g fat (of which 2g saturates)
4g fibre and 3.2g salt
Ingredients
 12 boneless chicken thighs(1kg/2lb 4oz in total), skin and visible fat removed sunflower oil spray  For the crispy coating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Duck with Duck-Fat Potatoes and Pickled Cabbage</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-11-22-duck-and-potatoes-with-red-cabbage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-11-22-duck-and-potatoes-with-red-cabbage/</guid>
      <description>The potatoes should be cut very finely here, so that they almost melt into the duck fat. A sharp accompaniment, such as sauerkraut or the pickled cabbage, below, is essential to balance the gloriously duck fat-rich potatoes.
INGREDIENTS
Serves 4
 baking potatoes 3, large duck fat 180g rosemary sprigs 4 duck legs 4  For the pickled cabbage:
 red cabbage 400g white wine vinegar 125ml cider vinegar 100ml coriander seed 1 tsp soft brown sugar 4 tsp  Set the oven at 175C/gas mark 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes with Garlic and Comté</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-11-22-nigels-garlic-and-cheese-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-11-22-nigels-garlic-and-cheese-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Should you not be able to get hold of Comté, a semi-firm cheese such as Fontina or Emmentaler will work just as well.
INGREDIENTS
Serves 6
 smoked garlic 7 cloves double cream 500ml bay leaf 1 cloves 2 full-fat milk 200ml Comté 150g potatoes 4 medium, waxy fleshed (yellow) butter 30g  Peel the smoked garlic and cut it into paper-thin slices then put it into a medium-sized saucepan with the cream, bayleaf, cloves and milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Jane&#39;s Granola Bars</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-10-29-janes-granola-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-10-29-janes-granola-bars/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS
 1 cup white flour 1 cup whole wheat flour 1 1/2 tsp. baking soda, add more if you add a lot of extra ingredients…which I often do!! 1/2 tsp. salt 2 cups brown sugar (Splenda if desired) (or honey…use less than 2 cups) 6 cups oatmeal ( I use Speerville oatmeal)..large flake oatmeal, as natural as you can find.  MIX WELL THEN ADD: 3/4 cup oil and 1 cup of water and I always add 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flix Bakery Biscuit Recipe</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-09-11-flix-bakery-biscuit-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-09-11-flix-bakery-biscuit-recipe/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS
 300 grams of flour (25% of which should be made up of, if possible, Rye Flour; Wheat Bran; Oat Flakes; Sesame Seeds; Sunflower Seeds &amp;amp; Flax / Linseed) 200 grams of Oats 170 grams of Brown Sugar 230 grams Butter Apricot Jam for the &amp;ldquo;finger print&amp;rdquo;  METHOD
180 degrees C - 200 degrees C for 9 minutes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown Scones</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-26-brown-scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-26-brown-scones/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 6ozs plain flour 6ozs brown flour Handful of pinhead oatmeal and bran 4ozs margarine 1 teaspoon bread soda Buttermilk  Method
Roll it out as wet as possible.
Bake at 200°f for about 20 minutes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braised Pigs Cheeks - Nigel Slater</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-20-braised-pigs-cheeks-nigel-slater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-20-braised-pigs-cheeks-nigel-slater/</guid>
      <description>The accompanying potatoes produce a creamy, almost &amp;ldquo;wet&amp;rdquo; mash of a very soft and velvety texture. Serves 4.
Ingredients
 olive oil a little  pig&amp;rsquo;s cheeks 8 carrots 3 onions 2  red onion 1 celery 2 garlic 4 flour 2 tbsp  thyme a generous bunch orange peel a short piece bay leaves 3 red wine 1 bottle, rich and bold sugar or fruit jelly 2 tbsp or so  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braised Pigs Cheeks - Spanish</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-20-braised-pigs-cheeks-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-08-20-braised-pigs-cheeks-spanish/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 1-2 tbsp olive oil 1 large onion, finely chopped 800g pork cheeks (ideally Ibérico Pork), excess fat &amp;amp; sinew trimmed and cut in half 1 tbsp flour, seasoned with salt and pepper 2 garlic cloves, crushed ½ tsp ground cumin 1 tsp pimentón de la Vera (smoked paprika) 100ml sherry vinegar (I&amp;rsquo;d half this) 500ml beef or pork stock Handful flat-leaf parsley 400g can of butter beans, drained &amp;amp; rinsed 1 garlic clove 70-100ml olive oil  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savoury Rice</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-05-06-savoury-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-05-06-savoury-rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion 3 mushrooms 1/2 red pepper 1 tomato 1 x 10ml spoon oil 150g long grain rice 1 x 5ml spoon vegetable stock powder or cube 550ml boiling water 50g peas 1 x 10ml spoon curry powder  Method Prepare the vegetables:
 Peel and chop the onion Slice the mushrooms Deseed and dice the red pepper Chop the tomato  Fry the onion in oil until soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philly Pasta Carbonara</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-03-19-philly-pasta-carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-03-19-philly-pasta-carbonara/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for 6  600 g spaghetti 6 rashers bacon cut into stripes 180 g Philadelphia Light 2 egg yolks 3 stalks flat parsley leaves picked and chopped 300 ml vegetable stock shavings of parmesan to garnish  Instructions 1 Step
Cook the pasta according to the pack instructions. While it&amp;rsquo;s cooking fry the bacon pieces in a large pan, add the veg stock and simmer for a few minutes till the liquid is reduced by half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clonakilty Blackpudding &amp; Chorizo Stew</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-clonakilty-blackpudding-chorizo-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-clonakilty-blackpudding-chorizo-stew/</guid>
      <description>2 brown onions 1 clove of Garlic 2 heaped teaspoons of smoked paprika 280g Clonakilty Blackpudding Chubb 280g Chorizo Sausage 1 Can of Broad Beans (chick peas will also do) 1 can of chopped tomatoes 1 can of Irish Cider 1 sprig of fresh rosemary  What do I do? Finely dice all your onions
Chop your chorizo sausage into small cubes, set aside
Chop your Clonakilty Blackpudding small cubes, set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingernut and Chocolate Fridge Cake</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-gingernut-and-chocolate-fridge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-gingernut-and-chocolate-fridge-cake/</guid>
      <description>300g dark or milk chocolate, chopped 1 tbsp golden syrup 250g ginger nut biscuits 2 eggs, beaten (make sure they&amp;rsquo;re the freshest you have) Cake tin and parchment paper  And you’ll need to do these things:  Line the cake tin with parchment paper. Melt the chocolate and golden syrup in a large heatproof bowl over a saucepan of simmering water. Meanwhile, crush your biscuits in a plastic bag with a rolling pin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Chicken</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-mustard-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2017-02-13-mustard-chicken/</guid>
      <description>For seasonings  olive oil extra virgin olive oil sea salt black pepper  For the chicken  a few sprigs fresh rosemary 4x180 g higher-welfare chicken breasts, skin on 4 teaspoons Colman&amp;rsquo;s mustard powder 3 baby leeks, or 1 large leek 4 cloves garlic white wine 75 ml single cream 1 heaped teaspoon wholegrain mustard  Turn the heat under the frying pan up to medium. Pick and finely chop the leaves from the rosemary sprigs and sprinkle them into the pack of chicken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond slices pastry for Mince Pies</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-12-18-almond-slices-pastry-for-mince-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-12-18-almond-slices-pastry-for-mince-pies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 ozs Self Raising flour 4 ozs margarine 2 ozs sugar 1 egg  Mix in magimix until it comes together, turn out on to a floured board &amp;amp; roll quite thinly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot Cake</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-12-18-carrot-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-12-18-carrot-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups sugar 1 1/2 cups veg. oil (not olive oil) 3 eggs 2 1/4 self-raising flour 2 teaspoons vanilla essence 2 teaspoons cinnamon 2 teaspoons bread soda 1 teaspoon salt 2 cups of shredded carrot 2 cups flaked coconut 18 ozs can crushed pineapples drained 1 cup chopped walnuts  Method Combine sugar, eggs and oil &amp;amp; vanilla in a bowl. Stir in flour, cinnamon, soda &amp;amp; salt - mix well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Moriarty&#39;s Southern Fried Chicken</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-19-mark-moriartys-southern-fried-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-19-mark-moriartys-southern-fried-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 eggs 100ml milk 100g breadcrumbs 1 tablespoon cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons paprika  Note: Makes 8 Chicken thighs
Method Place the thighs on some tinfoil and season with salt. Pour 200ml vegetable oil onto the tinfoil and seal it up like a package.
Place in the oven at 120c for 3 hours. Remove and chill in the fridge
Next, remove the skin and bone from the chicken and roll up the meat in clingfilm like a sausage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Pepper &amp; Cherry Tomatoes</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-sweet-pepper-cherry-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-sweet-pepper-cherry-tomato/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 long sweet peppers 8 cherry tomatoes 1 clove of garlic, peeled 4 tabllespoons of olive oil salt &amp;amp; pepper  Preparation Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Wedges and Gorgonzola Sauce - Nigel Slater </title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-potato-wedges-gorgonzola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-potato-wedges-gorgonzola/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS 1 kg Floury Potatoes 8 rashers of Smoked Streaky Bacon 5 tbsp Groundnut or Rapeseed Oil 1 tbsp crushed Chilli Flakes 1 tbsp Smoked Paprika  for the Dressing 250ml Double Cream 150g Gorgonzola or Dolcelatte  (any blue cheese will work but milder &amp;amp; sweeter is better)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Mushroom Rice - Nigel Slater (4 people) </title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-baked-mushroom-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-baked-mushroom-rice/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS 200g Shallots 4 cloves Garlic 150g Arborio Rice Sprigs of Thyme 1 litre Chicken or Vegetable Stock Grated Parmesan Salt &amp;amp; Pepper  METHODTIPSTWIST</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gills Mushroom Tart</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-gills-mushroom-tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-gills-mushroom-tart/</guid>
      <description>River Cottage head chef Gill Meller&amp;rsquo;s mushrooms, pastry and pancetta, taken from the Hugh&amp;rsquo;s Three Good Things on More4. Hugh&amp;rsquo;s recognised a simple pattern that underpins so many well-loved dishes – that they are little more or less than three good things on a plate and in this series, he pursues that idea, experimenting with different flavours and textures.
Prep time10 - 15 mins
Cook Time15 - 20 mins
Servings2 - 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice&#39;s Stew</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-10-27-alice-s-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-10-27-alice-s-stew/</guid>
      <description>1.25 lbs Minced Beef
1 Bay Leaf
I chopped onion
4 large potatoes, chopped into even pieces
1 carrot chopped, into even pieces
1 small tin chopped plum tomatoes
1 x Oxo Beef Stock cube (in approx. 200ml hot water)
lightly brown mince in a little oil, add remainder of ingredients, simmer for 1 to 2 hours - until potatoes &amp;amp; carrot cooked. Season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Cake with Lemon &amp; Chocolate Flecks</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-01-21-apple-cake-with-lemon-chocolate-flecks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-01-21-apple-cake-with-lemon-chocolate-flecks/</guid>
      <description>by Sarit Packer &amp;amp; Itamar Srulovich from Honey &amp;amp; Co. The Baking Book (Saltyard books)
This is the cake I would choose above all others. It is my mother’s go-to cake, the one that was always on the kitchen counter. Although my wife made a few changes to the recipe, the essence &amp;amp; goodness are unchanged.
 Makes a 1kg (2lb) loaf cake Prep time 20 mins Cooking time 50 mins  Ingredients  2 tbsp whisky zest &amp;amp; juice of 1 lemon 2 apples (200g once diced skin-on) – I use Pink Lady apples 40g bitter chocolate (70% cacao works best here) 2 eggs 160g caster sugar 120g/130ml vegetable oil 150g plain flour 1½ tsp baking powder 1 tsp ground nutmeg 1 tsp ground fennel seeds (I always grind my own) a pinch of table salt  Method Preheat the oven to 180C/160C fan/gas mark 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentic Spanish Paella with Prawns Chicken Rabbit and Snails</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-authentic-spanish-paella-with-prawns-chicken-rabbit-and-snails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-authentic-spanish-paella-with-prawns-chicken-rabbit-and-snails/</guid>
      <description>Serves 2 Source of Recipe Paul Merrett Preparation Time 30 mins to 1 hr Cooking Time 10 to 30 mins
Ingredients 15ml/1tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 cloves garlic, peeled and sliced thinly 1 saddle of rabbit, cut into even sized pieces 1 chicken breast, cut into large chunks 3 raw king prawns, shell on 10-15 live mussels, washed and debearded 4 ripe vine tomatoes, chopped finely 200g/7oz Spanish paella rice large pinch of saffron 1L/1¾pt hot chicken stock 200g/7oz cannellini beans 10 canned snails 50g/2oz frozen broad beans 50g/2oz frozen peas paprika to taste 10 cherry tomatoes salt and pepper  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Malay Rice</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-07-12-chicken-malay-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-07-12-chicken-malay-rice/</guid>
      <description>2 chicken breasts, cut in strips, season &amp;amp; fry on high heat with some honey (1 - 2 teaspoons drizzled over) until brown - set aside.
In same pan fry two large chopped onions, cover while frying for some steam.
Add a chopped red pepper and 3 or 4 cloves of crushed garlic - fry for, at least, 5 minutes
Add 200g of sliced button mushrooms &amp;amp; continue to fry</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken with Green Peppercorns and Oyster Mushrooms</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chicken-with-green-peppercorns-and-oyster-mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chicken-with-green-peppercorns-and-oyster-mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>(serves 2-3)
Ingredients 4 chicken breasts 5g/1oz butter 1tbsp/15ml olive oil salt and crushed black pepper  Sauce: Ѕmall white onion, peeled and chopped 1 clove of garlic, peeled and chopped 100ml white wine 4tbsp green peppercorns, crushed small bunch parsley, finely chopped 125ml double cream olive oil salt and pepper  Garnish: 200g/7oz oyster mushrooms 1 clove garlic (peeled and chopped) small bunch flat leaf parsley, chopped 25g/1oz butter salt and pepper  Method   Season the chicken and cook in the oil and butter until browned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chloe&#39;s Chocolate and Ginger Flapjacks</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chloe-chocolate-and-ginger-flapjacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chloe-chocolate-and-ginger-flapjacks/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 200g/8oz soft brown sugar 200g/8oz butter 2tbsp golden syrup 350g/12oz whole oats 3tbsp chopped ginger in syrup 100g/4oz chocolate chips  Method Pre-heat the oven to 150C/300F/Gas Mark 2. Place the sugar, butter and golden syrup together in a saucepan and heat gently until the butter has melted, stirring occasionally. Take the saucepan off the heat and stir in the oats, ginger and chocolate chips, mixing thoroughly. Pour the mixture into a lined and lightly greased tin and press it out evenly using the back of a wooden spoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cornflake Cakes</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-cornflake-cakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-cornflake-cakes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200g/8oz chocolate 2tbsp/30ml golden syrup 50g/2oz unsalted butter ornflakes  Method  Melt the chocolate with the syrup and butter. Add enough cornflakes to mix. Spoon the mixture into paper cases and allow to set.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crusty Vegetable Pilaf</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-crusty-vegetable-pilaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-crusty-vegetable-pilaf/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4 Source of Recipe Silvana Franco Preparation Time 10 to 30 mins Cooking Time 30 mins to 1 hr
Ingredients 1tsp golden caster sugar 1 large pinch saffron strands 50g/2oz butter 30ml/2tbsp water 450g/1lb basmati rice 30ml/2tbsp vegetable oil 1 large onion 1 red-skin potato (about 250g/9oz) 1 small butternut squash, peeled, seeded and cubed 1 birds eye chilli 1 cinnamon stick  For the raita: ½ medium cucumber, peeled and chopped roughly leaves from small bunch of coriander and mint 142ml/¼pt natural yogurt ½ lemon, juice only salt and freshly ground black pepper  Method  Place the sugar, saffron, half of the butter and water in a ramekin or teacup and microwave for 1 minute until the butter melts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date and Toffee Pudding </title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-15-date-and-toffee-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-15-date-and-toffee-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Date and toffee pudding with caramelised bananas and the ultimate toffee sauce
 1-2 hours preparation time 10 to 30 mins cooking time Serves 6-8  Ingredients 150ml/5fl oz dark rum 1 vanilla pod, split in half and the seeds scraped out 250g/9oz chopped dates 125g/4½oz butter, softened, plus extra for greasing 125g/4½oz soft dark brown sugar 3 free-range eggs 150g/5½oz plain flour, plus extra for dusting 2 tsp bicarbonate of soda 2 bananas, peeled and thinly sliced demerara sugar, for dusting  For the toffee sauce 175g/6oz demerara sugar 1 tbsp golden syrup 1 tbsp black treacle 170g/5¾oz butter 500ml/18fl oz double cream pinch salt  Preparation method  In a pan bring the rum, 250ml/9fl oz water and the vanilla seeds to the boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date and Wheaten Scones</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-04-09-date-and-wheaten-scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-04-09-date-and-wheaten-scones/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients: 10 oz (284g) wholemeal flour 4 oz (113g) plain flour 1 tsp salt 3 tsp baking powder 1 tsp baking soda 4 oz (113g) butter 2 oz (57g) granulated sugar 1 egg beaten 8 fl (237ml) buttermilk  all conversions are approximate
Method:  Preheat oven to 220 C gas 7
  Mix all dry ingredients into a bowl, then rub in butter with your fingers until it resembles a crumble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch Apple Cake Recipe</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-02-01-dutch-apple-cake-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-02-01-dutch-apple-cake-recipe/</guid>
      <description>2 large eggs 8oz [225g] caster sugar 4oz [110g] butter, plus extra for greasing 150ml [5fl oz] creamy milk 6 1/2 ozs [185g] plain flour, plus extra for sprinkling 3 teaspoons baking powder 3 - 4 apples 1oz [25g] sugar Cream, to serve  For the cinnamon sugar&amp;hellip;
 1oz [25g] caster sugar 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon  [Half above measures is enough for 2/3 large servings]
Preheat oven to Gas 6 [200c/400f]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Chicken Stir Fry</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
      <description>281 calories 140g chicken breast 1 teaspoon olive oil 1 teaspoon chopped ginger 2 tablespoons chopped coriander 1 clove crushed garlic 2 teaspoons soy sauce Half a squeezed lemon  Cut chicken fillet cut into strips and fry all in non-stick pan, until browned and sealed
Add 50g sugar snap peas 100g finely sliced cabbage 160g carrots, cut into thin strips  And cook for 5-10 more minutes until chicken is cooked, adding water if necessary</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Mexican Pizza</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-mexican-pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-mexican-pizza/</guid>
      <description>358 calories 1 tortilla 2 tablespoons passata 90g low fat mozzarella  Then scatter with chopped vegetables [170g] Mushrooms, red pepper, courgette, red onion, aubergine and spinach all ok.
Cook in a hot oven [gas mark 7] for 10 minutes, top shelf [at home!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Roast Salmon</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-roast-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-roast-salmon/</guid>
      <description>304 calories 140g salmon fillet 150g cherry tomatoes [on the vine, if possible]  Bake at 200c for 15-20 minutes
Serve with 112g green beans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Roasted vegetable salad</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-roasted-vegetable-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-roasted-vegetable-salad/</guid>
      <description>188 caloriesMix together 150g cherry tomatoes 50g sliced courgette 75g sliced aubergine [or twice the amount of courgette] 160g sliced red pepper  Scatter with basil leaves and drizzle with balsamic vinegar.
Roast in a hot oven [gas mark 7] for 20-25 minutes.
Serve with 2 tablespoons parmesan [20g].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Seared Tuna</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-seared-tuna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-seared-tuna/</guid>
      <description>326 calories 168g tuna steak, seared in a hot griddle pan - no oil, use a squeeze of lemon if needed  Serve with 120g [whole] grilled small red pepper 100g sliced, grilled, courgette  Which have been cut into long strips and mixed in a bowl with a teaspoon of olive oil
Grill on a medium-high heat for 5 minutes each side.
Dress with a sqeeze of lemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Spiced Dahl</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-spiced-dahl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-spiced-dahl/</guid>
      <description>326 calories Fry 60g chopped onion in 1 teaspoon olive oil with a clove of crushed garlic and 1 teaspoon finely chopped fresh ginger.  Cook for 5 minutes Add half pint water, 50g dried, washed red lentils, a pinch of Cumin Coriander Turmeric Cayenne pepper Salt and pepper.  Boil for 20 minutes or until lentils are tender.
Serve with 2 poppadoms and 2 tablespoons of fat-free natural yogurt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FD Vegetarian Chilli</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-vegetarian-chilli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-19-fd-vegetarian-chilli/</guid>
      <description>378 caloriesFry a clove of garlic and half finely chopped red chilli in a teaspoon of olive oil.
Add a pinch of cumin and 20g chopped mushrooms and cook for 5 minutes, adding water if it sticks.
Add half a tin chopped tomatoes [200g] and half a tin of kidney beans [200g], stir and simmer for 10 minutes.
Serve with 2 tablespoons cooked wild brown rice [80g/113 calories]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbread</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-25-gingerbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-25-gingerbread/</guid>
      <description>8ozs plain flour 1 egg 3ozs butter 3ozs brown sugar 1 tablespoon treacle 1 tablespoon golden syrup 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon bread soda 1 teaspoon ground ginger a little milk [sour, if possible]    Sieve flour, salt, ginger and bread soda, free from lumps, into a bowl
  Melt the butter, treacle, syrup and sugar over a very low heat. Don&amp;rsquo;t allow to become hot, only warm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goats Cheese, Serrano Ham Tart, Parmesan Pastry</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-03-26-goats-cheese-serrano-ham-tart-parmesan-pastry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-03-26-goats-cheese-serrano-ham-tart-parmesan-pastry/</guid>
      <description>By Catherine Fulvio
For the pastry  200g plain flour, plus extra for dusting 100g butter, chilled and diced 2 tbsp parmesan, grated ½ tsp oregano, finely chopped 1 egg yolk 2 - 3 tbsp chilled water (may need less)  For the filling  2 large eggs + 2 egg yolks slices Serrano ham, cut into strips 1 red pepper, roasted, skinned and diced 100ml crème fraiche 150ml Avonmore Cooking Cream 120g soft goat’s cheese 2 tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hairy Bikers Minced Beef Sauce</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-20-hairy-bikers-minced-beef-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-10-20-hairy-bikers-minced-beef-sauce/</guid>
      <description>1 medium onion, finely diced 2 small carrots, peeled and diced 2 celery sticks, trimmed and finely sliced 9oz/250g lean minced bedd [less than 10%fat] 1 tbsp tomato ketchup 1 tbsp brown sauce 1/2 tbsp Worchester sauce 1 tbsp plain flour 1/2 tsp hot chilli powder 1/2 tsp dried chilli flakes [optional] 1/2 tsp freshly ground black pepper 7ozs/200g potatoes [par boiled] 1/2 pint/300ml beef stock [made with 1stock cube 3ozs/75g frozen peas    Put the onion, carrots, celery and beef in a large non-stick saucepan and dry-fry over a high heat for 2-3 mintes, until the beef is no longer pink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home made Energy Bars</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-08-22-home-made-energy-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2013-08-22-home-made-energy-bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Sunflower Oil – 120ml/3/4 cup Soft Dark Brown Sugar – 200g/1 cup Golden Syrup – 2 tbsp Peanut Butter – 1 tbsp Vanilla Extract – 1/2 tsp Sesame Seeds – 25g / 2 tbsp Sunflower Seeds – 25g / 2 tbsp Flaked Almonds – 50g / 1/2 cup Sultanas – 50g / 1/2 cup Chopped Dates – 50g / 1/2 cup Thick cut porridge oats/oatmeal – 225g / 8 oz  Method Sunflower Oil – 120ml/3/4 cup Soft Dark Brown Sugar – 200g/1 cup Golden Syrup – 2 tbsp Peanut Butter – 1 tbsp Vanilla Extract – 1/2 tsp  Melt these ingredients in a pan over a low heat until melted and mixed together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguine with Pesto and Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-linguine-with-pesto-and-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-linguine-with-pesto-and-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 maris piper or tohter large potatoes, cut into small cubes 60ml/4tbsp olive oil 2 cloves garlic, finely chopped 1 packet of dried linguine salt and pepper 150 ml/5¼fl oz vegetable stock 15ml/1tbsp mascarpone cheese  For the pesto: 2 bunches of watercress, roughly chopped 180g/6¼oz almonds, crushed 180g/6¼oz parmesan, grated juice of one lemon 175ml/6¼fl oz olive oil salt and pepper  Method  First prepare the pesto. Tip the watercress, almonds, parmesan and lemon juice into a food processor and blitz, gradually pouring in the oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martha Stewart&#39;s One Pot Tomato Pasta</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-04-19-martha-stewart-s-one-pot-tomato-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-04-19-martha-stewart-s-one-pot-tomato-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Serves 4 [2 in brackets]
Ingredients :  12 [6] ozs. Linguine (or any other dry pasta) 12 [6] ozs. Cherry Tomatoes (halfed or quartered) 1 thinly sliced [or chopped for Keith!] Onion 4 cloves thinly sliced Garlic 1/2 teaspoon red-pepper flakes 2 sprigs Basil 2 [1] tablespoon Olive Oil Salt &amp;amp; Pepper, to taste 4 1/2 [2 1/4] cups of cold water (36 fluid ounces [18])  Parmesan &amp;amp; Basil Leaves for serving</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal &amp; Raisin Cookies</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-04-03-oatmeal-raisin-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2015-04-03-oatmeal-raisin-cookies/</guid>
      <description>125g unsalted Butter
100g Caster Sugar
75g soft light Brown Sugar
1 egg, lightly beaten
170g Plain Flour
1/2 teaspoon Baking Powder
Pinch of Salt
2 tbsp. Golden Syrup
50g Porridge Oats
100g Raisins
Melt butter, add to both sugars and mix in a bowl.
Add syrup and beaten egg.
Sift flour, baking powder, salt and mix in with butter and sugar.
Stir in oats and raisins.
Mix well.
Spoon [tablespoon] onto baking tray lined with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Cookies</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2014-01-01-oatmeal-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2014-01-01-oatmeal-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 stick butter 1 cup light brown sugar 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla 1/4 cup water and 2 eggs well beaten 1 teaspoon salt 1 cup flour, sifted 1/2 teaspoon baking soda About 1 cup oatmeal Chopped nuts (walnuts preferred)  Directions Mix in order and drop on baking sheet. Bake 400° 7 to 8 minutes. Then run under broiler to brown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Pan Fry-Up Brunch</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-02-one-pan-fry-up-brunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-02-one-pan-fry-up-brunch/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:  calorie controlled cooking spray 250 g (9 oz) potatoes, peeled and cut into 2cm (3/4 inch) dice 3 bacon medallions, chopped 150 g (5 ½ oz) chestnut or button mushrooms, sliced thickly 2 medium eggs freshly ground black pepper  Method Spray a lidded non stick frying pan lightly with the cooking spray.
Stir-fry the potatoes for 3-4 minutes over a high heat until starting to brown at the edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shepherd&#39;s Pie</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-06-13-shepherd-s-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-06-13-shepherd-s-pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:  1 onion, peeled and finely chopped 2 carrots peeled and finely chopped 500g of lean lamb mince small handful of fresh thyme ½ tbsp. ground cinnamon 300ml low salt vegetable stock 1 tbsp tomato puree large handful of frozen peas 2 large potatoes, peeled and diced 2 parsnips, peeled and diced 2 tbsp butter small handful of grated cheddar 1-2 tbsp milk olive oil  Method: Heat the oil in a medium saucepan, then soften the onion and carrots for a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Omlette</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-05-26-spanish-omlette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-05-26-spanish-omlette/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:  500g new potatoes (peeled) 1 white onion 150ml Extra Virgin Olive Oil 5 / 6 eggs  Method: Cut potatoes into thick slices Chop / slice onion
Heat oil in a LARGE frying pan, add the potatoes &amp;amp; onion and stew gently, partially covered, for 30 minutes, stirring occasionally until the potatoes have softened.
Strain potatoes and onions through a colander into a large bowl (set strained oil aside).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable Chow Mein</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-vegetable-chow-mein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-vegetable-chow-mein/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 200g/8oz egg noodles 1tbsp sesame oil 4tbsp groundnut oil 2 slices root ginger, shredded 1 garlic clove, peeled and crushed 3 shitake mushrooms, sliced 50g/2oz mange tout, trimmed 4tsp light soy sauce splash of dry sherry pinch sugar small bunch spring onions, sliced 75g/3oz bok choi 75g/3oz bean sprouts sesame oil salt and pepper  Method  Cook the noodles as per the instructions on the pack.
  Rinse in cold water, drain thoroughly and toss in sesame oil to keep the noodles separate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey and peanut butter booster bars</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-honey-peanutbutter-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-honey-peanutbutter-bars/</guid>
      <description>125g unsalted butter 150g soft brown sugar or light muscovado sugar 125g no-sugar-added crunchy peanut butter 75g honey, plus a little more to finish Finely grated zest of 1 orange Finely grated zest of 1 lemon 200g porridge oats (not jumbo) 150g dried fruit, such as raisins, sultanas and chopped apricots, prunes or dates, either singly or in combination 150g mixed seeds, such as pumpkin, sunflower, poppy, linseed and sesame    Preheat the oven to 160C / gas mark 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refrigerator Double Chocolate Cookies (makes 12)</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-refrigerator-double-chocolate-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-refrigerator-double-chocolate-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125g/5oz unsalted butter at room temperature 70g/2 1/2 oz caster sugar 70g/2 1/2oz demerara sugar 1 egg 140g/5oz flour 1/2 tsp bicarbonate of soda pinch of salt 50g/2oz dark chocolate, cut into chunks 50g/2oz white chocolate, cut into chunks 80g/3oz toasted hazelnuts, roughly chopped (optional)  Method  Pre-heat the oven to 160C/325F/Gas 3. Cream together the butter and sugars, then beat in the egg. Sift together the flour, bicarbonate of soda and salt, and mix in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-belgian-chocolate-fridge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-belgian-chocolate-fridge-cake/</guid>
      <description> 6 ozs unsalted butter 12 ozs crushed digestives 3 ozs chopped nuts 3 ozs raisins 3 ozs sultanas grated rind of 1 orange - OPTIONAL 3 tablespoons golden syrup 4.5 tablespoons drinking chocolate powder.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chilli Con Carne</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chilli-con-carne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-chilli-con-carne/</guid>
      <description>1 1/2 tablespoons vegetable oil 1 medium onion, peeled &amp;amp; chopped 1 medium RED pepper, seeded &amp;amp; chopped 1 1/4 lbs minced beef 2 cloves of garlic, peeled &amp;amp; finely chopped 6 ozs tomato puree 200 ml chicken stock (1 stock cube) 1/4 teaspoon ground cumin 1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper 2 teaspoons chilli powder 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon salt 2 x 15 oz tins of kidney beans  Method  Cook onion, pepper, beef &amp;amp; garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Chicken Curry</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-creamy-chicken-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-creamy-chicken-curry/</guid>
      <description>2oz 50g Butter 1 small onion, peeled &amp;amp; finely chopped 1 small apple, peeled, cored &amp;amp; finely chopped 2 tablespoons plain flour 12 fl oz 340ml chicken stock 4 fl oz 115ml double cream 1/2 teaspoon salt 4 teaspoons of curry powder (I only use 3 teaspoons of Schwartz Medium Curry) Pinch cayenne pepper 1/4 teaspoon ground ginger 1 1/4 lb 575g diced cooked chicken / turkey  Method  Melt the butter in a large, heavy frying pan over moderately high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Chicken Dip</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-creamy-chicken-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-creamy-chicken-dip/</guid>
      <description>100g / 4 ozs cooked skinned chicken 2 crushed garlic cloves 150 ml / 1/4 pint of mayonnaise 2 tablespoons tomato puree salt &amp;amp; pepper  MethodProcess chicken, add garlic, mayonnaise, puree &amp;amp; seasoning until well blended. Serve chilled.
Serve with crackers / melba toast / crudites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagne / Bolognase Sauce</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-lasagne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-lasagne/</guid>
      <description>1 pack of Streaky Bacon 1 lb minced beef Onion Carrot Mushrooms 1oz butter 1 or 2 rounded table spoon of tomato puree 8 fl oz dry white wine 1/2 pint beef stock teaspoon caster sugar salt 1 1/2 pints Bechamel / White sauce Shaved parmesan / cheddar cheese for topping Lasagne / Spaghetti  If lasagne, throughly butter a shallow dish - meat, sauce, lasagne until all used up - finishing with sauce - then sprinkle cheese and bake in centre of oven (gas mark 6 / 400F) for 15/20 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Pate</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-mushroom-pate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-mushroom-pate/</guid>
      <description>6 ozs mushrooms 1 oz onion 1 oz butter 4 ozs cottage cheese crushed clove of garlic    Chop mushrooms, melt butter in pan at medium hear &amp;amp; cook chopped onion until soft. Raise hear, add mushrooms and cook for a further few minutes. Place all ingredients in a blender &amp;amp; blend until smooth. Press pate into serving dish &amp;amp; chill before serving.
  Serve with crackers, melba toast and / or crudites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risotto</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-risotto/</guid>
      <description>Chicken / mushroom / both etc. 1 litre / 2 pints chicken stock 55g / 2oz butter 2 tablespoons Olive oil 1 / 2 onions, finely chopped 285g / 10oz Arborio / Risotto rice 100ml / 4 fl oz white wine 55g / 2oz fresh grated parmesan cheese  keep stock simmering - melt 1oz butter and the olive oil, add onions &amp;amp; cook. Add mushrooms &amp;amp; cooked chicken.Add rice, turn up heat &amp;amp; add wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice Cooking Times</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-rice-cooking-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-rice-cooking-times/</guid>
      <description>Rice Water 75g 200ml 150g 400ml 188g 500ml  11 Minutes full power allow to stand for 2 minutes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Furlong&#39;s Crunchy Biscuits </title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-mary-furlong-crunchy-biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-mary-furlong-crunchy-biscuits/</guid>
      <description>4oz porridge oats 4oz self-raising flour 4o4 butter 3oz demerara sugar 1 dessertspoon golden syrup 1 rounded teaspoon ground ginger  Method  Pre-heat oven to 170C, Gas 3
  Heat butter, sugar, syrup over getle heat until sugar dissolved.
  Sift flour into mixing bowl. Add porridge oats, ground ginger. Pour in melted mixture and combine thoroughly.
  Roll small quantities into small balls. Put on graesed baking trays and press down to flatten.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
