<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>potatoes on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</title>
    <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/tags/potatoes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in potatoes on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://thebluebayou.github.io/tags/potatoes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Skillet Potatoes with Chorizo and Fried Eggs</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-skillet-potatoes-with-chorizo-and-fried-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2019-09-15-skillet-potatoes-with-chorizo-and-fried-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 750g baby potatoes, cut into quarters 1 tbsp rapeseed oil 1 large onion, thinly sliced 2 garlic cloves, finely sliced 125g chorizo ring, sliced thickly 1 tbsp fresh rosemary, finely chopped 270g Vittoria tomatoes, halved 4 eggs ½ tsp chipotle chilli flakes  Method
  Preheat the oven to 200°C/gas mark 6. Boil the potatoes for 10 minutes until tender. Drain and leave to cool.   Meanwhile, heat the oil in a large skillet or shallow casserole dish and add the onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguine with Pesto and Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-linguine-with-pesto-and-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2012-01-01-linguine-with-pesto-and-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 maris piper or tohter large potatoes, cut into small cubes 60ml/4tbsp olive oil 2 cloves garlic, finely chopped 1 packet of dried linguine salt and pepper 150 ml/5¼fl oz vegetable stock 15ml/1tbsp mascarpone cheese  For the pesto: 2 bunches of watercress, roughly chopped 180g/6¼oz almonds, crushed 180g/6¼oz parmesan, grated juice of one lemon 175ml/6¼fl oz olive oil salt and pepper  Method  First prepare the pesto. Tip the watercress, almonds, parmesan and lemon juice into a food processor and blitz, gradually pouring in the oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Pan Fry-Up Brunch</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-02-one-pan-fry-up-brunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-11-02-one-pan-fry-up-brunch/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:  calorie controlled cooking spray 250 g (9 oz) potatoes, peeled and cut into 2cm (3/4 inch) dice 3 bacon medallions, chopped 150 g (5 ½ oz) chestnut or button mushrooms, sliced thickly 2 medium eggs freshly ground black pepper  Method Spray a lidded non stick frying pan lightly with the cooking spray.
Stir-fry the potatoes for 3-4 minutes over a high heat until starting to brown at the edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shepherd&#39;s Pie</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-06-13-shepherd-s-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2016-06-13-shepherd-s-pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients:  1 onion, peeled and finely chopped 2 carrots peeled and finely chopped 500g of lean lamb mince small handful of fresh thyme ½ tbsp. ground cinnamon 300ml low salt vegetable stock 1 tbsp tomato puree large handful of frozen peas 2 large potatoes, peeled and diced 2 parsnips, peeled and diced 2 tbsp butter small handful of grated cheddar 1-2 tbsp milk olive oil  Method: Heat the oil in a medium saucepan, then soften the onion and carrots for a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
