<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>soup on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</title>
    <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/tags/soup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in soup on Flo&#39;s Food and Drink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://thebluebayou.github.io/tags/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-14-french-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2021-02-14-french-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS
 3 pounds sweet onions, thinly sliced 4 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted 2 teaspoons brown sugar 2 teaspoons sherry vinegar 1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce 5 fresh thyme sprigs 3 bay leaves 6 cups beef stock Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 (12-ounce) French baguette, sliced 2 cups Gruyère cheese, shredded  Method
Add the thinly sliced onions to a 6-qt slow cooker. Stir in butter, brown sugar, 1 teaspoon salt, sherry vinegar and Worcestershire sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NI Vegetable Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-ni-vegetable-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2020-10-31-ni-vegetable-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 500g soup vegetables (2 carrots, 5 sticks of celery - including the leaves, 2-3 leeks &amp;amp; flat leaf parsley) 100 - 200g marrowfat peas (soaked overnight), lentils, barley 2 / 2.5 litres of stock - vegetable &amp;amp; chicken Salt &amp;amp; Pepper  Method
Make stock, add peas (lentils/barley) bring to the boil &amp;amp; simmer gently for at least 20 minutes (until peas tender ish)
Add chopped vegetables &amp;amp; bring back to the boil and simmer for at least 25 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-12-11-recipe-for-french-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thebluebayou.github.io/recipes/2018-12-11-recipe-for-french-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>WHOLE CHICKEN STOCK
 1 whole chicken (about 4 to 5 pounds), remove any paper or big fat globs inside the bird 1 yellow onion, quartered 2 carrots, scrubbed and cut in half 2 celery stalks (with leaves if possible), cut in half 5 garlic cloves, smashed open, skin removed 2 large bay leaves 5 sprigs fresh thyme 5 stems fresh parsley 1 tablespoon sea salt 1/2 teaspoon whole black peppercorns water to cover chicken – at least 4 quarts  METHOD</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
